

# Patrick Michl

Senior Data Scientist | Al Engineer | Mathematician





### **PERSONAL**

Contact Floringasse 5, 69117 Heidelberg, DE

Phone: +49 177 85 44 151 Email: patrick.michl@gmail.com

**Legal** POB/Date-: 93309 Kelheim, DE at 05/19/1982

Nationality: German Marital status: Married

Online Professional profile: <u>LinkedIn</u>

Research profile: ORCid | Heidelberg University

Software development: <u>GitHub | PyPI</u> Blog/Talks: <u>Frootlab | SlideShare</u>

Certificates: Credly | Coursera | Scrum.org



### **ABOUT**

I spent the most part of my professional and educational lifetime by shaping my experience and expertise in AI, machine learning, software development and network technologies. During this process I gained domain specific insights into different industries comprising manufacturing (engineering, shop floor and office), finance (office, sales) and pharma (research). I identify myself as a passionate mathematician, obsessive software developer and convinced AI enthusiast.



#### **EDUCATION**

# Ruprecht-Karls-Universität

Heidelberg, 2006 - 2018

Mathematics Diploma: Grade 1.4 / GPA 3.6, with specialization in statistics, machine learning and differential geometry. Subsidiary subjects: Theoretical physics, applied computer sciences and systems biology. Fundamental <a href="research">research</a> in machine learning and systems biology with honored <a href="diplomathesis">diplomathesis</a>: "Principal Manifold based Correlation Analysis"

#### Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule

Regensburg, 2003 - 2006

Applied mathematics with specialization in graph theory, optimization and operations-research. Subsidiary subjects: Relational database management, software development and economics. Internship semester: Development and implementation of the graph-based optimization algorithm and software "PolyTran" for automated machine translation.



#### **LANGUAGES**

German: Native | English: Fluent | French: Basic | Irish: Basic



#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### amprela GmbH, Senior Data Scientist

Mannheim, 05/2021 - present

Process mining, enterprise data modeling- and digitalization projects from inception to agile project management, implementation and operation

#### reboot GmbH. Data Scientist

Mannheim, 03/2020 - 04/2021

Al driven shop floor automation, business analytics, database development and digitalization projects comprising predictive analytics and RPA

#### Freelance Data Scientist

Heidelberg, 03/2018 - 02/2020

Consulting in enterprise data warehousing, (hybrid-, multi-) cloud, data analysis- and digitalization projects in the Rhine-Neckar metropolitan area

## Frootlab Smart Analytics, Founder

Heidelberg, 05/2016 - present

Founder, software architect and consultant for the next generation low code software framework "Vivid Code" for automated collaborative computing

#### Ruprecht-Karls-Universität

06/2008 - 02/2014, Institute for Mathematics, Systemadministrator: Unix administration, DB administration, network configuration and security

05/2012 - 07/2012, Institute for Molecular Biotechnology, Research Assistant: Deep-learning-based gene expression analysis

10/2008 - 03/2009, Institute for Computer Sciences, Lecture Assistant: Applied CS and programming at software engineering research group

#### DKFZ, Research Assistant

Heidelberg, 12/2012 - 01/2014

Research in deep-learning-based gene regulation analysis with application to breast cancer and GBM at the network modeling research group

## Eckert Schulen, Freelance Technical Writer

Regenstauf, 10/2011 - 09/2012

Authoring of the textbook: "Netzwerktechnik", NET(TE)1, ArtNr. 02303, for the vocational education of IT- and electrical engineers in germany



#### **SKILLS**

Machine Learning | Statistics | AI | Data Visualization and Presentation Statistical Programming (Python, SAS, R, Matlab) | Business Analytics Predictive Maintenance | Process Mining | Network Technology / Security DB Dev (SQL, noSQL) | Cloud Dev (Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Spark) Web Dev (TypeScript, Angular, PHP; REST) | Administration (Debian) IT Project Management (Scrum)